foreign
Technologies in an ever-changing digital
marketing space well ladies and
gentlemen to cut the cheese and not
introduce the topic because I feel the
moderator is going to do a brilliant job
with that it is my honor to call upon
somebody who always
has a new trick under his sleeve
he would either come as a clone
or have has his own virtual Avatar I've
Seen It All I've witnessed it all he
brings a new flavor every single time on
stage ladies and gentlemen the head of
mobile and emerging Tech emerging Tech
lead wpp India group M India let's give
him a big big round of applause
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you nidash for joining us
well with that if I may have the CMO of
Raymond Consumer Care Puja sahigal
do we have puta in the room right now
actually yes she's right there come on
ladies and gentlemen a big big round of
applause
thank you Pooja
the chief marketing officer Hershey's
Ankit Desai
thank you Ankit for joining us
[Applause]
[Music]
the director marketing category loyalty
and digitals Tata Starbucks the very
vibrant Deepa Krishnan
foreign
the founder and CEO question what's real
Suraj
[Applause]
while leaders will truly question you on
what's being real out here
[Music]
he creates it for you
[Applause]
head marketing corporate communication
and CSR ICICI Lombard Sheena Kapoor
foreign
[Applause]
and the head brand building Ultra Tech
cement kanupriya thatvania
[Applause]
[Music]
well I'm excited to see Niraj how you've
curated this entire conversation ahead
over to you thank you so much
we keep doing this
so it's so usual
all right so thank you so much this is
the last session I think uh you're
planning with Indian television we
thought the last session and it's going
to be traffic so people are going to run
away
but we still have like really decent
crowd so thank you so much for making
time
which is quick one I've been doing this
uh emerging Tech and now we call it uh
Creative Tech for more than a decade now
and uh people keep asking me like what
really motivates you to keep deep diving
into blue oceans and how do you actually
go about convincing your client because
there's so much risk out there
so
first thing there is and I would urge
all my colleagues and everyone is to you
have to constantly create prototypes you
know and go back to them and say that
this is not far away from you this is me
this is my clone and that's what bhana
was saying that I ended up creating
so much content in the last two years
especially in the covet phase that I got
awarded for the most admired digital
content creator Yesterday by World
mobile Congress right so I mean I even
didn't know I was actually constantly
creating content because I thought maybe
when I create content and go back to
kanupriya Puja my friend Ankit and all
of you all there will be like a very
strong resonance in terms of yeah this
is closer to us this is doable you know
it's my clone talking to them and and
more so what I started doing is I
started creating clones of our
leadership as well so two and a half
years back I created my first clone ever
which took me about 10 hours of original
content right so I had to actually sit
and read
from the teleprompter in front of me for
10 hours and shoot with a white screen
that allowed me to create my clone and
that clone then went on WhatsApp to all
my friends and my leadership saying that
randomly talking to them and then I then
I asked them okay the guy who was
talking to you wasn't me it was actually
my clone and that excited a lot of
people and we ended up creating our
first uh celeb clone with Hrithik Roshan
and then we did uh our most popular
campaign right which had creativity at
heart so kudos to Ogilvy for bringing in
that campaign Ogilvy and wavemaker
together delivered this campaign which
one has Global Glory titanium Lions ever
India has ever won right so Shahrukh
Khan not just a Cadbury ad you guys are
all aware right and recently what I
believe is this power of this platform
is to add language models to it so my
clone is being around this is a seventh
edition of my clone but now watch my
clone speaking in various languages
right so I can personally speak English
Hindi and Gujarati fluently but you will
now see me speaking in various other
languages which is which is what I'm
really bullish about when it comes to
synthetic AI which is like edition of
language models so let's play The Av
please
foreign
so I don't know how how many of you
understand some of these languages but
imagine if you were to go really micro
in India and like all these top brands
here they've got really popular
celebrities imagine Amitabh Bachchan
interacting in Karnataka in kannada you
know this is me with seventh attempt not
that accurate this can go further
accurate in times to come right so
multiple language models are already
getting added we are talking about
generative AI now so if you see our most
uh trending campaign of AI video
regeneration we did it for ages Federal
where we recreated the young Sachin
Tendulkar if you follow that right the
16 year old Sachin Tendulkar was being
recreated using AI so there are tons of
Innovations which is happening in this
space so we thought now across forums
wherever I go and I do the talking what
I personally feel is uh this record
number of tech interventions which are
happening in today's times right
what we are trying to do is we are
trying to devise a solution for every
audience type wherever they are and
whatever kind of device they own so if
we talk about India we're talking about
1 billion active mobile connections in
India and we still say India has got
record number of feature phones right
close to 350 million not feature phones
there are emerging Tech interventions
which apply to feature phones also to
smartphones also through tablets and
bunch of other platforms which are
evolving over the years right so to kick
start this panel and the way I have
curated it is all my friends and
obviously Suraj does a lot of creation
for me across metaverse and web 3
environments and we recently concluded
last year uh Nestle was where we did an
IPL fan meet so the IPL players and top
60 lucky fans were inside the meta was
jamming and stuff like that right so now
these experiences are also getting
completely transformed
2022 we saw metaverse experiences which
was more riding on the metaverse wave
and we created a lot of meaningful
experimentation right from Moon dating
on Mondelez to the first wedding ever on
the metaverse to doing holy in the
metaverse and stuff like that right this
year and inspired by my boss Andy Hood
he did a campaign for Bastille globally
where fans could not just enter the
concert but their avatars can actually
pop in inside the concert and they can
Hi-Fi the lead protagonist right so that
makes it really special now we're
talking about India with 5G Computing we
will actually have the next level of
meta human pops happening on live
concerts now imagine one of the use case
which I'm working on is this typically
when you see this IPL Cricket
environment someone from Bihar calls up
and says
all right that's the kind of fan meet
which is happening in today's Times
how about me sending
a complete mocab driven portable Studio
to top 10 fans of IPL across India
someone sitting in Bihar where's the
mocap pops right next to Virat Kohli and
Virat Kohli is teaching him how to play
it you know a meta human
in the actual Studio environment so
that's the level of computing we are
going to apply in times to come and 2023
you will see metaverse experiences which
will drive scale for us look at the
number one concert globally right which
keeps spoken about Travis Scott with 27
million people attending and not even
one person entered through a headgear
everyone entered through mobile phones
so we'll also talk about project which
Puja is working on on Karma was or what
Hershey's currently launched a metaverse
experience so there's tons of work which
is happening on the nft space as well
clearly the nobility value has faded but
we are constantly looking for utility
value when it comes to nft and we'll
talk some of it how Puja and team have
clubbed clubbed it with the
conversational media and create given it
a twist with an nft angle right and then
we've got Sheena who's doing and my
conversation with her yesterday it's a
mind-blowing work on how drone is being
put to action right as well as VR and
that were a bfsi category Lombard is
clearly a reader there so I would I
would start with kanupriya first and we
would start from the bottom of the
pyramid which is those feature phone
users and what kind of take intervention
are we building for those audiences out
there on voice AI as a core practice so
kanupriya would love to hear from you on
bhagi which is our Star product which is
one Smarties X by the way ladies and L
man you will rarely see a cement
category brand making all the way
creating Global headlines such kudos to
the content also the way they have
strategically positioned it like
Wikipedia of Home Care that is what we
call it
would love to hear
thanks Niraj as usual uh you blow us out
with the tech we can use and make us
marketers salivate for more uh so I
think uh thanks for the introduction but
I represent a category uh which
everybody uses but nobody really sees
and very bottom of the pyramid so cement
is a ubiquitous uh not really branded in
a way and used more in Rural and small
town India than any of us I think if I
go around the room nobody would have
built their homes you would have bought
your homes or renovated your homes but
very few would have built their homes
taking that queue we went ahead and with
creativity content reach and scale these
were the four uh mantras if I can call
it that for bgk uh is a series which got
started to teach about home building now
how do you teach people who are in a
remote village with only access as their
feature phone uh I think from a tech
angle the there were three that we
deployed one is of course using
vernacular how do I go across nine
languages with 200 pieces of content
that I have and put it out there in an
audio format so that people can access
it when they want to so we did this
along with one is the serve that we did
the other one was with the jio network
and both have really worked wonders for
us for both listening to the content as
well as repeat wanting it so we had a
toll-free number where we people could
call in and ask for more content how do
I now take it to feature phone out of
feature phone onto a handheld device
which is uh
has some data you know we are used to
our postpaid plans and having unlimited
data in a way this audience has limited
data so it's important that I serve them
what they want uh some use of AI and ml
helped us in personalizing the content
that if somebody's watched a piece of
content what is the next likely for them
and serving that up to them so uh those
kind of media nudges including of course
a mind share did a stellar job of
contextually targeting when they want it
through you know General stuff that we
use with his banners and to say that
okay you're here this is what you might
need and redirect so I think some simple
use I would still keep it that since we
are still like Niraj says bottom of the
pile but we've had to really innovate
along with our partners to get to the
bottom of the the file there and give
them an experience which they desire
because to our world there is no rural
in urban there is people who have
mobility and the people who don't so I
think the applications are Mindless and
we can not you know just mindlessly use
you know some of the tech which is
available there so we've had to pick and
choose and uh bgk has given us an
opportunity to not just show creativity
but reach at scale uh that's the one
question that gets asked of tech that is
it going to give me reach and scale so
uh these are the two three things that
we were able to do to towards content
marketing
absolutely I think the technology in the
rural pocket and if you were to see how
device set is evolving now to Smart
feature phones as they call it we are
also seeing a lot of video Bots getting
launched on feature phones now which are
again multilingual in nature the classic
example is unilever's mobile doctor knee
which runs in about six languages runs
on a base level feature phone and that
to a video output kind of a stuff right
so it's constantly growing and we're
also seeing a trend of marketeers not
deploying an omni channel strategy not
wise only because there are device sets
which are upgrading if I'm sending you a
communication and if you have WhatsApp
on your phone I would stay Regional but
I would send you richer communication
through WhatsApp and the initiator can
be a regular call as well now another
area of work which is picking up is this
entire social conversational space right
I'm trying to get geared a bit and
taking the conversation further and Puja
is getting geared also to give that
answer is this entire space of uh social
conversational marketing and emojis is
kind of driving the wave right no more
when I were to give a thumbs up to
someone I would rather give a thumbs up
as a brand going as an emoji rather than
a regular thumbs up so you're already
seeing a keyboard level marketing 100
million plus users all the regular
emojis are getting converted into brand
LED emojis and there's where Puja and
team have done a phenomenal job so let's
up the ante from feature phone to
slightly
you know young category and uh what you
call scalable audience on low end
smartphones if you were to see the
number 65 percent of those 600 million
smartphones are in the population
bracket of 10 to 15 000 and you
dominates that category right and very
very high engaging kind of an audience
out there and they live on these emojis
they cannot really make it viral and
share it so any use case I think you
have a brilliant use case and an amazing
brand
thanks thanks neeraj so uh yes so it is
not a very young category it's a very
old category uh Kama Sutra so I work on
Kamasutra condoms and of course what we
figured out is that while sex is one of
the most searched terms it is also one
of the terms you use very less and you
know people are not very open about it
so we wanted to basically take our brand
which is you know a bit old-fashioned
compared to Durex Etc and said how do we
make it really modern and relevant so we
tied up with Bobble and basically we
know that the young consumers are really
floating they're far more free what they
say to each other on the phone and
through WhatsApp so whenever any
conversations came about about love sex
relationship we made sure that a
Kamasutra Emoji was interspersed within
the uh you know conversation so it was
very contextual it was not first it
really helped them actually Aid in the
conversation and help build a
relationship with each other and we not
only stopped at that so of course you
know we we reached around seven million
uh we had seven million conversations we
had great engagement but those were the
days of nft also so we took a most
engaging stickers and we minted nfts
with it so around six nfts and we
actually sold those nfts uh you know
much to our surprise also and it did
extremely well and we donated that to a
social cause so which also helps in you
know birth control so it was a really
well-rounded or you know event and
activation which again really helped
Drive our brand in the context of
youngsters in the very right context so
definitely uh I think tech provides that
big engagement and reach and roly also
helps Drive brand imagery it's not in
either role
absolutely that's why we keep talking
about creative and Tech coming together
for us to deliver fabulous fancy sci-fi
campaigns right it cannot be only a
takeout approach it needs to be blended
with creativity in a big way now talking
about web 3 I would say one of the most
brilliant use cases of web3 is loyalty
and Deepa and the Starbucks team have
been doing some spell job in that space
not just in India but I think globally
and now extending it to India so just to
set a context metaverse again seems to
encapsulate everything right all the
work which uh Ankit is doing on
Hershey's all what he's launched but it
encapsulates AR VR Mr blockchain nfts
Virtual Worlds it's a large subject and
when I talk about web3 the core utility
which I see is loyalty which is what
brands like Starbucks and YSL have
recently mastered so would love to hear
what are your thoughts how are you guys
building a sustained program and I think
one of the few Brands who are now
thinking more sustained approach when it
comes to web3 and not just right hiding
on a PR wave obviously we created a lot
of meaningful experimentation but it was
more tactical in nature nothing was more
sustained this year we're looking at say
scale and sustained programs so we'd
love to hear this use case there will be
a lot of learning for our audience as
well
sure I just want to say at this point
that this is my clone this is not the
real me the real the real Deepak
Krishnan is sitting at home avoiding all
the Mumbai traffic so this is just a
clone that's a disclaimer first of all
having said that so you know my belief
is and in India we have a 2 million plus
loyalty program Starbucks so we have
huge First Data first party data that we
have access to
um to be in a sense a spoiled spot in
this party I will say that your
technology is meaningless if you don't
have solid first party data okay and
what do you do with that data because
today there's no dearth of data the
problem is what is the analytics
framework you want to use to interpret
that data in a meaningful manner
um so on our loyalty program we try and
get into a segment of one with analytics
so we you know do a very extensive
recency frequency monetary kind of
segmentation where we are able to
understand consumer Behavior right up to
their favorite beverage time of the day
they'll come to a store weekday weekend
which is their favorite store Etc and
all of this data which is then in a
sense handed over to our store partners
with the consent of the customer because
privacy is again a very very important
aspect then the buddhista is able to
have more fruitful conversation so let
me give you an example if I already know
that you need a fan of Americano I'm
just making up stuff here you look like
an Americano guy so I'm taking the
liberty of saying that if I know that
you're an Americano customer my Barista
kind of watches you enter the store
knows that he or she has to get the
Americano ready
and that's further reinforced by swiping
your card on the pause the point of sale
and then the Barista can have a more
meaningful conversation with you saying
you know which is your new clone which
is the new language you're practicing
Etc right so there's a point of
connection
um we've used this data very extensively
to have conversations with the customers
one-on-one send them personalized videos
on our 10th anniversary more than four
lakh personalized videos you know
talking about the Journey of our
customers Etc in the U.S Starbucks is
pioneering Starbucks Odyssey uh maybe
some of you would have heard of that
which is really an experience based on
metaverse and nft which will only be
restricted to the Loyalty program
members and the nft that will be mined
will be used to get rewards on the
program in India we have launched our
first Reserve store in Mumbai in October
last year Reserve is really a high-end
format and there we've actually used
augmented reality very well the walls of
the store will talk to you and you have
living murals in the store I'd urge you
to visit that so I think to sum up I'd
say that first the fundamentals you have
to get right Pure Play technology
doesn't help so get your first party
data dissect it get to a segment of one
and then use technology as an exp
appearance enabler for this absolutely
so just just to take your point on
augmented reality clearly if you want to
talk about extended reality as a subject
augmented reality is the most right
platform I would say and in India it's
firing up in all three categories of
augmented reality whether it's in-appar
web AR or your social ER you go to
places like insta you go to any Ecom app
you'll be able to now place the
furniture in real life and see and that
that's how the ROI goes to the roof
right look at flipkarts move of
acquiring skeptic and bunch of other
Ecom platforms you will see a strong leg
of AR Commerce there on the in-app side
and another another interesting platform
is niantic's eighth wall as as Deepa
mentioned about the first party database
and the world moved towards the idealist
World more and more marketers are now
gunning to curate first party database
and one of the ways to do that is
Weber which is getting driven on top of
your packs you know some of some of the
oldest brands in India have got reach
more than mobile look at Clinic plus
would have more reach than in Bihar than
mobile phones right so your on pack is a
very powerful vehicle put it put a web
AR on top of it and you will see some
amazing Renditions out there Asia
doesn't have a volumetric studio
capabilities right now at initial level
imagine that comes to India then look at
examples like your Coke bottle you can
have Ranbir Kapoor popping onto Coke
bottle and you can have a live
interaction with Ranbir Kapoor that
requires a volumetric capture with him
so your celebrities can come alive on
the pack and there's this magical piece
of simple technology which is being
around for ages which is Quick Response
codes QR codes everyone knows about it
and I think you've leveraged it in a big
way right uh Ankit so just talk us
through how you've leveraged QR codes
and Suraj here is a big believer of QR
as well so maybe you can add to it I
actually got scared when you use some
very fancy what was it done
no no before that some eight eight
Niantic eighth one so I thought he's
gonna ask me something yeah it's a huge
started looking very very popular
platform eighth wall is a company got
acquired by Niantic one of our Global
Partners post this I need to update
myself but jokes right uh chocolates is
a fun category but it is also very close
to Indians for for obvious reasons so
what we do is technology becomes an
enabler versus the destination for us it
is important to first pick the occasion
the contextuality what's the mindset of
the consumer and then participate in it
and I'll give you a couple of examples
so
um Valentine and women's day uh
Valentine obviously is all about gifting
so we keep it simple so there is a QR
code which allows you to express
yourself and you build in Tech through
it uh it's sort of a physical experience
what we did is you buy a pack you you
know Proclaim your message the message
got displayed on ground and there's
obviously a closing the loop
gratification as well
uh because Valentine is fun you want to
express and then so this is the this is
an established occasion for the category
uh women's day women's day was not an
occasion for the category but we thought
that there was something intrinsic in a
brand name so I don't know how many of
you would know but like the word her and
she goes unnoticed in the brand name
Hershey's likewise the achievements a
lot a lot of her and she around us go
unnoticed so we said what other occasion
but women's day to celebrate it so we
kept it very simple uh we had all we had
a complete packaging takeover where we
celebrated almost six heroes from
different walks of life and we said they
don't need to celebrate shiros who are
Achievers only you can celebrate anybody
so I would celebrate Puja I'd celebrate
Sheena and that was enabled through very
seamless experience so there was a QR
code on Tech uh you scan the QR code
you'd go on the portal you can you would
send a message to a Shiro and then she
would share it so it's as simple is that
and both doing meeting different
objectives bases the contextuality
through very seamless experience
similarly we said it's Christmas it's
fun time end of the year we launched the
Hershey was
where again the intent was just to make
people have fun obviously Hershey was if
I'm not wrong currently the number of
users are 20 odd million but expected to
be 150 million so at this point in time
that was more a topical thing but we are
really hoping that Hershey was has got
20 million uh cut that out in terms of
in terms of
metaverse users from what I know India
the number is around 21 20 odd million
who actively engaged in metaverse unless
I've got my numbers is it much more yeah
no no no that's not the number okay
that's the layer Mandy quoted a number
on Kapil Sharma show he is no more I
mean he's there
is very very nascent there are very
minuscule numbers on metaverse as of now
it's exactly what internet was in 2003.
another two three years we are
discussing metaverse it's still going to
remain Nation but the infrastructure
that supports metaverse it's constantly
growing look at Amazon Prime Netflix
Sony here Suraj is working with Sony's
Eternal metaverse the series of concerts
which are coming in right everyone's
building for it but the audience set is
very very limited right now
yeah so that's the state of Art
so 20 million
I'll come to you
so yeah I think that's the uh it's
coming back as long as you're creating
an experience which is uh contextually
relevant to the TG
seamlessly done and an end objective in
mind text should be an enabler versus
saying I want to do something yeah and
which is where we found QR code to be
quite effective contrary to what one
would think and the kind of
participation we get actually runs into
thousands and possibly touching a lag as
well absolutely you here who's a big
believer of QR code and how would I get
into QR codes like let me just do the
fact brief again right yeah so in terms
of metaverse users uh you are right when
you say that there are about 21 million
users just to get the audience up to
speed on that right there are two sorts
of people looking at metaverses one are
marketers and the others the general
gaming audience
if you ask a gamer what is a metaverse
he would say that it's just a
multiplayer experience a multiplayer
experience I've been playing multiplayer
games for like 20 years now right I have
developed and worked on about four or
five multiplayer games those were also
meta verses I could meet a friend inside
the space I could compete with them I
could interact with them and everything
now what has happened is people have
gotten a lot more freedom to just
socialize the metric is no longer a game
the metric is just living because you
know we saw a pandemic and then in the
pandemic a lot of people felt very
isolated inside boxes and then these
games allowed them to express themselves
in the same way they would generally do
right and that's the metric that you're
mentioning when you say that 20 million
yes there are 20 million metaverse users
in India it is just that they are not
sitting on the meta verses that you guys
are looking at which is you know your
four uh about the gaming worlds like
Roblox so consider this right that GTA 5
even though it's a brutal game has
substantial amount of players in India
it is the simple fact is that marketers
find that as a difficult or a risky
platform to really Market themselves but
still like uh I learned most of my stop
blocking experience on GTA 5 because it
has an entire Stock Exchange I have a
stock stock exchange portfolio on it no
risk right you can just keep trying and
it's a real Stock Exchange there are
other players also investing and the
same way that it works in the real world
these fictitious companies have their
own you know up and ups and downs that
happen inside the space so a real life
experience that I got out of a metaverse
where metaverse itself weren't relevant
right is what I wish to just tell the
audience that dude this thing has been
there the thing is that two different
sorts of people from two status of
society are looking at it yeah and
that's yes kids are totally living on
Roblox like you would see tens and
millions of people on platforms like
Roblox and my son has created a library
on Minecraft and I asked him why he says
my friends will come and check out my
collection right so that's the kind of
conversation a seven year old is doing
so if you were to see the gaming worlds
which are coded on top of this would you
call those gaming engines like unreal
you are seeing like tons and tons of
destinations where there are already
kids who are going and playing games
yeah but can you go and sticker that
environment and run ads out there the
answer right now is a big no you've got
to create immersive brand mascots who
would go and play around this space and
connect with those audiences like we did
Wendy's right it was a virtual character
which moved in and challenged every game
was like us and beat us at that right so
that's the kind of advertising which
would be part of the metabus destination
especially the gaming ones
now uh coming back and question to use
Suraj because we've been building a lot
of these metaverse experiences how will
it all change in 2023 what kind of scale
are we looking at what will be the
experience with uh kudos to 5G Computing
our life will change so uh India in
general is a leapfrog economy right when
you even look at data metrics of QR
adoption we have numbers that are just
not making sense to most of the
marketers outside of the sandbox so the
same thing is going to happen even you
know when it comes to 5G adoption now
when you talk about this screen sitting
in your pocket right you're already
getting 4K Ultra HD video from Netflix
on 4G network so what is the true
utility of 5G when we talk about 5G
that's where Mia niras mostly have our
fights right the fact that computers in
the future are going to be worn on
people's heads they're not going to be
sitting inside people's pockets because
when you wear a computer on your head
which is primarily like a virtual
reality headset or augmented reality
headset that primarily unlocks a lot
more potential of consuming data as well
as relaying back your expressions or
emotions or whatever like today I Tap a
button to you know express myself
tomorrow I'll actually be able to give
my thumbs up and the way I give my
thumbs up and the way neeraj does a
thumbs up is substantially different and
emojis have you know made that into a
single Silo where you're probably able
to just pick the color of your skin
that's the only thing that is able
you're able to customize but then you
know when neeraj gives me that high five
there is a different feeling I have
right and that's emotional feeling has
to be translated through these digital
sandboxes that's the whole point as to
why we are building them so from that
point of view uh I think that tier two
tier three has a substantially larger
option like we are in we have been in
the space of uh Hardware manufacturing
we manufacture a lot of VR headsets we
have seen more headsets being adopted in
places like kohima and nagaland honestly
speaking the when I made my first
dispatch I actually drove all the way to
kohima to see who the hell are these
people buying these headsets right and I
was substantially surprised to see that
there are extremely highly technically
literate people willing to put down the
top dollar to try new things because
that's what they think makes them cool
but then in Bombay everybody you know
has this idea that oh yes
there are more VR users in nagaland
then in Mumbai yeah like daily active
users and substantially like if you even
if you look at my sales numbers most of
my sales numbers come from tier-to-day
audiences than tier one like we have set
up over uh like today uh our
organization at least uh enables about
over a lack of students in India in KV
schools across the country and have used
VR headsets as a textbook replacement
the simple fundamental point is when
Comics were relevant I used to like
reading and when cartoons came in my
Comics book became right and there is a
there is a very thin line like from the
baijus model itself why did they gamify
education because kids are now addicted
to games and gamification of Education
now gets that child to get the best of
both worlds while saving the same amount
of time right so I think now is the time
in 2023 when VR becomes more sorry when
5G becomes more ubiquitous that more and
more people will be able to adopt to
this kind of tech because I think the
only everything that is limiting right
now is the network speeds and this thing
will just disrupt that space and again
coming to pixel streaming pixel
streaming allows people to have like you
know heavy duty computers that cost like
40 50 lakh rupees inside a smartphone
right and that kind of horsepower
primarily is required for larger
organizations to be able to you know use
the power of 5G and let's see what 2003
has for us absolutely so Suraj mentioned
about a very interesting utility of VR
which is how education is getting driven
through creative Hardwares there are
kids in sitting in nagaland who are
actually studying putting on those VR
device and the education which you get
on VR is Sensational right I mean it's
more immersive and you'll never be able
to forget what you learn through VR
devices now let me bring in Sheena here
and she's being quiet for a while
because we had like really intense
conversation a really busy panel Sheena
is being using some really murky
technology stack whether it's drone or
VR to engage the first party database
which she has which is what Deepa
mentioned that it's critical to build
first party database and once you have
that what do you do with that and and
here's a classic use case of a bfsi
category ICICI Lombard who's used this
to Perfection using technology at the
heart but capitalizing on the one PD
which you guys are building
right thank you Niraj and thank you for
having me here
um and I'm I'm hoping the audience is
enjoying as much as I have listening to
my co-panelists and before I answer your
question in fact I'm thinking insurance
as a category right it's about covering
risk and when she was talking about
cement I was obviously thinking about
the property of the house somebody built
and you go about okay that's the asset
that is getting insured and you spoke
about drone and here is a drone that's
actually doing an inspection to check
during flooding whether the roof got
flooded or not rather than actually if
there was a flood or an earthquake
situation where you had to physically
manually send somebody a surveyor to
actually inspect the damage or assess uh
the extent of risk uh covered let's take
Hershey's as an example right now he's
sending chocolates as cargo Transit
maybe he's sending it you know to far
parts of the country maybe overseas as
well now you Marine Transit cargo
Transit is again something that we as an
insurer would cover as a risk but what
AIML allows us to do from a data
capturing is I'm looking at critical
parameters in terms of humidity in terms
of temperature control in terms of if
there has been any exposure even if
there has been any meddling with the
cargo because we have put detectors
there to be able to
pre-empt any kind of theft or damage
even before it occurs and then if it
actually occurs you're able to actually
assess again the damage uh to it you
know you spoke about Kamasutra again I
was thinking that okay that's sexual
health and mental health we have I'll
take care as you know a mobile app where
insurance today is actually again
capturing biomarkers genetics genomes
and as and how the health stack keeps
getting more and more advanced more and
more uh Progressive in terms of
capturing a lot of the data
um and you know insurance irda has just
uh from January first made it mandatory
from a kyc standpoint that it'll get
linked even your insurance policies will
go and follow the route of dmat the way
Securities and stocks are you know
Incorporated and stored which allows the
entire ecosystem of data getting
captured and therefore that entire
ecosystem of data being enabled for an
insurer or an underwriter or an actuary
or a surveyor to actually look at the
parameters and the risk profiling of the
consumer
um and you know similarly I mean I could
just go on even when we use the drones
from an inspection lens we are looking
at say an agriculture or a crop
insurance you're talking acres and acres
of land where it could have been a
flooding situation there could have been
a climatic situation that has you know
uh erupted or caused a certain damage
now if you imagine and visualize in the
traditional sense where you had a
physically a team of two or three going
to assess acres and Acres different
terrains of land ubitara is climbing
Hills and you know trying to capture and
note down and record or videotape on his
this thing is tons of data it's very
inefficient suddenly drones have allowed
you to capture this at a very granular
level actually do an entire heat map and
geospatial mapping and that's how we're
able to from an underwriting perspective
and insurance companies are able to
evaluate the risk even on VR right what
we decided to do was let's take an in a
situation where you have a property
there is an SME there who has a factory
who has a business and you want to be
able to safeguard the goods or the
premises so there are two scenarios
where we use the VR headsets where we
don't want to go physically whether it's
on time cost or efficiency metrics we do
a remote scanning where we get uh you
know a 3D simulation of the entire
premise or the factory and actually
assess and are able to build a case for
insurance and highlight this is the
Hazardous you know fear this is where
you know your fire could leak out this
is where you know the gasoline this is
where your kitchen is this is you know
from the layout perspective and then
you're able to even when the claim
arises again you're able to Overlay the
pictures whether captured through drone
and overlay that with the pre-damage on
Factory of the premises and that's how
you're using VR to remotely sit and
assess the entire damage and actually
underwrite what is the extent of
settlement that you need to do and then
we went a step further saying we're
since we're using drones might as well
ensure the drones as well so we went
ahead and offered a drone insurance and
then we said hey there's all this data
that is getting you know stored which is
valuable let's go ahead and offer
Insurance to store uh you know cover
that risk and that's how you have cyber
risk that's come into play so all of
these actually are you know
interconnected now we spoke about I
agree there's climate risk so therefore
as an insurance company that's a risk we
are willing to cover climate risk as
well
um so yeah those are just some of the
isn't that fabulous how many of you guys
were aware about lumbar doing this right
using drone and VR2 Perfection this is
I'm one of the fans and Loyalists for
Hershey so I'm a convert already
was constantly nodding saying that how
do I interfere into this similar
audience somewhere
take this I think it's interesting for
me because a lot of the
audiences that we talk to haven't really
even heard of mobile phoneme WhatsApp
so uh but we have a different audience
so as Ultra Tech we do B2B marketing and
we talk to B2B clients uh all the uh
rail will know this in terms of real
estate guys uh across different cities
and we are trying to work there in terms
of giving them experiences of uh and
what connected with me was risk
management uh what AI can do I think is
to give you an environment where you can
risk free try something yeah and cover
that risk so I think that somewhere
builds in to say that when the person is
building a house is building it for one
time once I pour that cement in it's not
going to be replaceable and that's a
risk at the end of the day do I have I
done it properly is my contractor doing
it properly all those questions are
asked once a layout is done how do I
de-risk that and I think that's a great
case for this guy to you know who can't
even visualize a WhatsApp message to be
able to go through
it'll look like this or if it's a
sloping slope where I'm making my home
how does that work out can I put in jio
data in it and today there are some
parts we are doing uh but it's the
Computing is done in our brain and we
don't have enough data sources to make
it easy for my field guide to actually
help saying that they go you know
and hence this is what you can do this
is how it visually looks like I think
the future is exciting uh with 5G Tech
coming in what always happens 3G and 4G
will open up for my rural audiences and
that makes it exciting that's what
happened when 3G and 4G happened so
suddenly rural audiences can have better
experiences yeah so uh yeah I think if
we can get scale added I'm signed in
all right so guys we have about three
minutes either we can round up our
conversation with a point of view on how
Tech would evolve or we can take
questions
questions Anil is right here and we have
got so many questions uh what role do
you think I mean there's been a comment
Trend people are talking about chat GPT
and everything what role do you think AI
or judge video or judge Beauty clones so
many of them are coming can play in this
space over the next few years you think
Chad GPD what role would it play play
yes
so uh you know the entire objective of
AI is to really give humans Wings right
that's what they generally market so the
real reason behind that is there are
still a lot of mundane repetitive jobs
like consider the fact that you know
call centers right consider that job as
a subset right you don't really have a
quality life there you're doing
repetitive calls and you know it's just
happening over and over and even on that
the human element keeps getting
demotivated like you can easily gauge
that
is
right so that and it takes a lot for a
human being to you know sit on that and
there are people I know who are doing
800 900 calls yeah it's the same script
Nothing Changes and on top of that there
is no context like the person is just
talking like a robot a human talking
like a robot here a robot will be able
to talk like a human right and it will
be able to do that at a pace that you
you can't like you your brains can't
comprehend and I think that same logic
now comes from a tutoring point of view
a counseling point of view a sales point
of view or marketing point of view where
a lot of these mundane tasks and mundane
jobs would get replaced by Ai and people
would be just sitting there supervising
these things so that you know a little
bit of at least human element is added
to it right even though it's doing a
pretty phenomenal job just being a free
open source system right now
talk show my clone is actually running a
presentation for a client and my team is
managing it so seriously mundane task
let them do it we'll do interesting work
questions
so uh so I come from a education and
career counseling kind of a field and I
talk to a lot of parents who whose
children are in the 13 14 15 16 age
group and so there is this uh constant
dilemma that is there that on one hand
uh you know there is this school of
thought that says that let children be
in touch more with um you know with the
physical interactions and social skills
and emotional skills and play and art
etc etc and keep them away from gadgets
and on the other hand there's such a lot
of things like gaming and metaverses
entering into mainstream careers and
applications of Education I mean they
have being applied in education for
disseminating education so so any
thoughts on that because I see a lot of
confusion around in parents and
Educators about should we encourage
technology you say should be dissued or
what to do and then it just as it is you
know so any any thoughts
it's a perspective and you know we all
can join
I think it has to be Best of Both Worlds
and I would use the word balance so
taking technology away from the kids uh
is is not going to happen but I think
drawing the right balance allowing them
to have the physical as well as uh
digital experience
while obviously there are certain
guardrails because most brands like we
give our kids yeah absolutely and when
most brands participate there are clear
guard rails which we maintain because we
are also conscious about what the kid is
exposed to so it is here to stay and it
should be used effectively
um yeah that's that's that's my
perspective and use it in a way that it
enables the child
uh while also giving him or her that
relaxation on the that uh free space
like just to add to that right consider
a field like architecture there was a
time when CAD models were made the size
of this room right today it's been
digitized so I don't think and you know
any person can become a architect like
at least a mediocre one right the
specialized ones will pay more attention
to detail but it does not restrict a
neeraj or a suros to try right try a
simulated model to see if I am liking it
or something like that previously it
would have taken this the same child too
much pain to convince themselves to sit
and try and draw something on a piece of
paper
um that's one point the second point was
I actually graduated from a design
school right and I don't know how to
draw
and I will stop on the class I still
don't know how to draw most of the
people in my classroom were people who
could draw really really well and I was
just like no man I'm good at a mouse and
a keyboard and I can really kick ass
with that and I've done pretty fairly a
good job so it's and today when I go and
do some Consulting for a logo design I
don't need to sit on a piece of tissue
paper or a piece of paper and start
sketching I can directly start
prototyping on a computer and in the end
of the day the final product that I'm
gonna submit to my client is going to be
a digital file and not a physical copy
of anything right
officials as well yeah yeah you're
digitally signing documents as well
today right your signature mismatch
problems like from that point of view
but if you think more from education
point of view the education which you
get through VR I'm repeating it's
Sensational you will never the student
will never be able to forget what he's
learning and what we have learned the
way we have learned those copy book
Style
it is useless now I would say VR
education is the way to go
for really sharper connect and and the
way they are coaching art students art
students are there government is funding
those headgears they come and there is a
VR day where they come and they we are
not saying it's always on
but imagine again
you'll never forget it that is that is
what the power is yeah so a data point
for you uh especially in the terms of
Education right so the nagaland prospect
again there was a KV school about six
kilometers away which had not gotten
into this program uh and there was a KV
school which already had gotten into the
program what we noticed was there was a
30 growth rate in terms of the academic
score that the average child had in this
school versus that school for the same
curriculum that was taught one in VR and
one on a black uh Blackboard so 30 is a
substantial amount for a tier three
audience to you know claim especially in
a uh bear vernacular medium uh school so
I hardly like you know that like I can't
you know think that I still have to keep
going back to the past I need to now
Focus to the Future so the objective is
just to convince these parents that
like you can't you know go back to it
actually a big believer on camera Focus
marketing
have you seen AR edutech Google lens and
how they are driving education have you
ever experienced it it's free for all it
is so mind-blowing
you will never forget it what do you
learn Google is investing on it in a big
way
so I think this needs to be yeah
questions
just one more uh so Nike had raised
close to 1500 1500 crores from the nft
sales do you think Brands can look at
this as a monetizable thing in the
future in India also or is it going to
be more of an engagement exercise
the nft lady on the panel but yeah I I
don't think nft making money the nft way
is the way to go you've got to look for
the core utility
considering the current regulations
yeah I think some iconic Brands like
Nike depending on the theme they do of
course you know you can make money out
of it but Brands like uh us are really
using and motor Drive engagement and
interaction and also write with the
existing Trend but having said that yes
I think maybe luxury Brands I have seen
not only Nike but even Chanel Gucci they
have really made a lot of money you know
minting this and like we say uh I think
the future is endless and there's a lot
of potential uh so I'm sure nfts will
come back so even we for example are we
you know are launching our Karma bus
with a bot not as exciting as neeraj but
just somewhere close and one of the
things will be in nft gallery because we
know there are huge number of people in
India who are engaging with nft want to
unleash their creativity and technology
is now democratizing that so I think
eventually yes why not you know it could
be a great way for people to be famous
to that art and that could be sellable
like you know great Brands by riding
into a theme can come up with Concepts
which you know could help generate money
so number of brands from Chanel Gucci
and all and Nike using themes have been
able to really you know commercialize
this very well okay near it I have a
question social tokens is way to go
yeah so I'm sorry I'll just add one
thing to that I
have brands are going to look at nft2 's
money yeah
therefore creating brand love and
engagement yes money is a side outcome
you know and if there is something which
is very iconic you know like Puja
mentioned then of course those Brands
will think but I don't think any
marketer is going to say you know nft is
a future Revenue stream so let me look
at it they are going to want to form a
very strong connect with their customers
and therefore give their fan base or the
creme de La Creme of their customers
something unique which they can always
have so it's a part of digital
participation and extending your brand
love rather than a monetary stream
here
you know we're talking about Innovation
lab kind of experiments right now I call
them experiments I don't call them asset
option so they are there any marketing
problems which are common as Garden
which can which needs Solutions in terms
of technology which we haven't addressed
I'm these are these are lab ex I call
them lab experiments what are they doing
oh just come again are there any
marketing problems yeah which are
communist problems common is uh Garden
in their you know you face them every
day but for which we still haven't found
technological solutions oh okay it could
be simple thing like uh
like you're talking about uh measurement
this morning they were talking about
measurement yeah that is any problem
which hasn't found a solution which
a technology company can find a solution
for
it could be data Gathering the first
major reaction is this um serving ads on
the OEM inventory
yeah really good inventory but you
cannot serve on their platforms like
glance of the world
yeah I I just want to uh so what uh as
Ultra Tech I think you are one of the
largest vendors in the country today
both on TV digital and other media uh
radio and Digital radio Etc uh the big
challenge that is there is if I park for
one for one moment efficiencies
Etc uh digital by definition is
measurable how do I do that to an analog
platform and my consumer today is Omni
Channel and Multiverse uh how do how
does technology help in you know
stitching that up from a marketer's
Viewpoint one is the experiences that we
create and the potential products that
we can bring out and help our consumers
with the other is the work that we do to
to enable the ROI for my organization I
think from the back end work one is this
in terms of getting some amount of
overlap and not pissing off my consumer
if I can say that by huge ad uh you know
with a huge amount of inventory out
there there's advertising pouring
through my nose even on WhatsApp these
days so I think and Brands don't want to
do that uh I think we want to put it out
there for people who are relevant
technology needs to find a way to do
that that's one of the problems yeah in
fact that's a great question uh I think
one opportunity area is research
consumer research so of course there's
been huge Evolution but I think that
that giant leap in terms of always on
Research uh knowing what the consumer
wants pre-post uh is a huge opportunity
which
currently is not enabled by Tech as to
the extent which one would want and
especially so let me let me just add to
it for a lot of my clients when we have
beta we have to beta tester product now
imagine when you are creating an
application for Rural India
right and they don't know 50 50.
you know these are learnings when you go
and speak to them then you understand
and personally if you ask me technology
and creativity would have a solve for
any marketing problem
at least I believe I think that way as a
emerging Tech practice lead you've got
to be positive in that approach one of
the brand gave me a task to Target many
truck owners who are coming and parking
their vehicles outside sabji Mandi
location in 150 locations no one
approached that we cracked it through
Telco intelligence
someone who is coming to sabji Mandi
location two times someone who has a
feature phone to internet users to your
Regional languages
so I'm saying
area in your space
where you if you don't have forget it
yeah her category is like super spiced
up solution is solution
okay
good category spiced up so much you can
do right you know you're limited in what
you can showcase because sex is a bad
word in India yet it's the most searched
word in India so so I think your
question is uh you know what is
technology not able to solve for
marketing right or whatever it hasn't
solved and it can solve so I think I
would just say you know we can use our
imagination I feel Tech can solve
tomorrow what we can't imagine today
right so your question I was thinking
about um was that blood droplet that
film which which didn't happen uh they
tried to she tried to fool everyone I
forgot the name of that uh what was that
she she's in jail she just went be in
baths recently sorry yes so you know
what I'm talking about right so I think
I think it's about imagination so to
give you an example of yeah it is about
how you know we used to reach people
through earlier television and now I
think technology is really enabling us
to talk one-on-one so how do I really
understand what what you're saying uh
what you really need and how do I break
those barriers you know to to come uh
and you know to help solve what you're
really looking for so I think tomorrow
to me you know as we were talking
the goal post goes on changing so if we
visualize what we really want to solve I
think people like Niraj and the team
will put together a road map on you know
aiming to solve it so I think it still
goes to human problems so like for
example
um I mean this is all very commercial
but uh you know the way technology like
we spoke about is now democratizing
education so you can look at something
good you can look at something bad it's
about how you use it to really Drive
which is really important in India the
sense of equality and democratization so
I think for me that is the biggest role
of Technology you know breaking barriers
uh and as I have progressed in the
marketing world or also progressed in
life I mean become older actually I've
seen the way technology has democratized
I look like you're 16. you're not
growing older I'm forgetting I'm in the
panel I'm thinking Solutions you know
like use generative AI to create a sex
education platform so that's what we are
doing so we're Reinventing uh karma
sutra we call it hours and the beauty
everywhere what we were saying people
are talking about tier two tier three
you know Metro tier one is gone whereas
earlier we were only talking about Metro
on tier one yeah so I love the way
technology actually has really got reach
it's called scale it's made everything
so accessible we know there are one
billion jio phones you know roaming
around pretty soon and I went for
another talk where they told me today
people are more video literate than they
are literate and we just step out of our
buildings and we see the BMC cleaners
actually using their video phones while
they're cleaning so I think technology
is an amazing democratization tool and
it's really exciting to see what unveils
tomorrow so maybe even the droplet of
blood can diagnose all our diseases very
soon yep see now you want to add to it
actually I could think of quite a few
problems I'd love to hear all the
problems so starting and I'm talking as
a marketer and I'm sure a lot of my you
know panels and members here could think
of it and not to say that we don't have
the solutions today it it's you know
it's some time away but it's there for
instance if I've released an ad as a
brand in print
as simple as me forget readership right
forget the number of households if I
really want to be able to at a very
granular level Target how many people
actually read my ad yes I could put a QR
code and get the person to interact and
get him to a landing page or whatever
but that level of accuracy I don't have
the same thing is there in certain
inherent media limitations same thing
for instance for an outdoor I'm spending
a bomb month on month on some key
outdoor investing not spending please
investing month on month okay a bomb
depending on you know where the hoarding
is right and yet and what I'm getting is
a footfall and I'm getting an estimation
and it's an extrapolation
therefore so many eyeballs it is getting
so efficacy is what you're looking for
I'm looking at accuracy in terms of
measurement in terms of the eyeballs
technically if you had
um you know just like on digital you're
able to very granularly measure you
can't do that with a lot of other
traditional media two
today in spite all of these years okay
we don't have a single technologically
available solution that gives a very
accurate attribution model
as a marketeer you have various Channel
points you've got outdoor you've got
exhibition you've got print you've got
radio you've got your branches you've
got your call center there is no you
know tool available to a marketer saying
this is the accurate attribution model
in terms of leads or in terms of Revenue
contribution fourth
as consumers are getting more and more
digital right somebody like me is
actually a god cutter and it's a it's a
dichotomy uh you know and it's a paradox
because as a marketer I want to consume
ads and messages but when I'm consuming
content I'm very clear I want it on
demand and I want it non-intrusive so
I've chosen you know a YouTube which is
on premium Sans any ads you know I try
and clear stay close to office or even
if I'm you know traveling I'm on the
iPod or on my mail so I'm not viewing
outdoor I've stopped going to theater
I'm only on Netflix I don't have cable
for the last eight years I'm only on
Amazon and Netflix and Ott content how
does anybody Target me I'm not reading
newspapers I'm consuming news which is
coming on in shorts right so as the
court Cutters it's a very you know
minute Community Niche Community but
this community is going to increase
increase because this community demands
on-demand content so I could go on that
there are a lot of substitute go on
please I'm willing to absorb no but I
think in the end
I think I think I would say this is a
wrap yeah media investment Summit this
was a super engaging conversation I
could again respond to this with an
attribution model which is in the
pipeline we don't want to do that
because this is not an attribution panel
conversation but we had a rich
conversation like really it got extended
and I can see all of you all we are
looking are still with us which is I
love it you know it's like a mic drop
moment when I dropped the mic he's like
but you know we're gonna still go ahead
yeah one final question
I mean you you guys
knows me I'm currently at MX Player and
would really want to understand what
emerging Technologies do you think will
be the best fit for otd players I know
like very I mean hardly anyone is
promoted and needed review the best
person to answer that so yeah
yeah it makes ways of what emerging
technologies will be best fit for Ott
from consumer experience perspective and
from revenue perspective since I'm from
sales strategy team so
[Applause]
thank you
no no I would say so there needs to be a
constant innovation in the Ott space as
well and mxp I would rank it right there
because we did our first interactive Ott
campaign on Ax with mxp where the xdo
where the user gets to decide right
click one right click one yeah so user
gets to decide which way is the story
going the girl is proposing it to you
you will decide the user will decide
whether you say yes or no and the story
would move in that direction right
Netflix similar we replicated here so I
think there is a room for constantly
innovating the insight for that was
Amazon Fire stick remote in covert times
people were spending three hours on the
fire stick remote and that's when we
thought there was a need to
use that inside and create a solution on
interactivity
anyone wants to add to it I think it
needs to be constantly innovated is what
I personally feel you know it seems like
half the panel is sitting half for
standing
I would like to
please go ahead so like I think passive
content is already almost dead right
meaning the largest social media
platform is telling you 15 second shots
so Ott is already on Long format so what
you need to only focus on is not make it
passive meaning make it interactive yes
we have seen use cases like these and
possibly that's primarily how content in
Long format will evolve that is that the
audience wants to participate rather
than not because we already have like
for example I used to watch when I was
living as a bachelor in China I used to
watch 20 25 minute videos to learn how
to make a sabji today I watch it in 15
seconds and I know how to make it 25
minutes of Time Versus 15 seconds
yeah like other than that like of course
immersion has its own metrics but then
when you talk about specifically Ott
content I think interaction is the first
step that you need to take and make it
more active than passive which is just
sitting and watching a television that's
the only 10 cents I wanted to add